Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
I asked you to go get the corruption for me, didn't I?
（カルタフィルス）
僕は あの澱(よど)みを
回収してこいって言ったよね？
You have that much trouble with a simple errand?
お使いも 満足にできないの？
Well, fine.
まあいいや
I did get to have a glimpse of him.
思いがけず
あいつの様子は見れたからね
If you don't want apprentice
to be turned into an ingredient,
君の弟子を
材料にされたくなかったら
次は うまくやっておいで
don't mess up next time.
Master, why do you listen to that psycho?
なんで あんなイカれたヤツの
言うことを聞くんですか？
腕まで取られて！
He took your arm!
You don't need to concern yourself.
（レンフレッド）
お前は何も気にしなくていい
A master protects his apprentice.
師匠(ししょう)は弟子を守るものだ
信頼してくれ
Have faith in me.
But...
（アリス）でも…
It's fine.
（レンフレッド）
大丈夫だ　考えはある
I have a plan.
Wasn't I supposed to protect you?
あたしは
あんたの護(まも)り手じゃなかったのかよ
One mandrake petal.
（チセ）
マンドレイクの花弁が１枚…
Please.
お願い
Sound, sound through the night forest.
響け 響け 夜の守歌(もりうた)
Sing, sing, young hawthorns.
うたえ うたえ サンザシの子
Let your thorns pierce the creeping hooves.
忍ぶ蹄(ひづめ)を お前の棘(いばら)が刺すように
（エリアス）チセ
Chise.
When do you think you can finish the
order for the old lady at the foot of the hill?
坂の下の
ばあさん用の注文
いつ出来そう？
（チセ）ちょうど
I just finished mixing a pint of hops and
five leaves of lavender for the insomnia pillow.
不眠用の枕は
ホップが１パイント
ラベンダーが５枚
And this is an enchanted
potion for warding off nightmares.
こっちは 悪夢を避ける
まじないの水です
（エリアス）
ふむ
教えたとおりだね
Just as I taught you.
You used too much magic.
It's turned into a sleeping potion.
魔力 使い過ぎて
眠り薬になってる
Work a little harder on the proportions.
もう少し 調整 頑張って
Okay.
（チセ）はい…
（チセ）難しいな
This is hard.
Since I learned of his goal, Elias seems to have decided
（チセ）
私が彼の目的を知ったことで
エリアスは私に
to begin seriously teaching me magic.
本格的に魔法を教えることを
決めたようだった
What has an effect on what, what needs to
be helped along, and what needs to be avoided...
どんなものが
どんなことに影響するのか
何を助けて 何を遠ざけるか
Strange traditions from long ago.
奇妙な習わし 古くから伝わること
Things that can be both medicinal and poisonous.
薬にもなり 毒にもなるもの
Wooly bugs, aethonic...
（チセ）綿虫… アエトニキ…
Chise, we're going out for a while.
（エリアス）
チセ ちょっと出かけるよ
Okay.
は〜い
A black dog?
Yeah.
Also known as a church grim.
墓守犬(チャーチ･グリム)とも
呼ばれるけどね
教会と墓を守る
優秀な番犬だよ
An excellent watchdog who
protects the church and the graveyard.
One seems to have made
himself at home at a nearby church.
近くの教会に
居ついたらしくて
Our task is to see if he's hostile or not.
僕らは
そいつが無害かどうか
確かめなきゃ
ならないのさ
There are hostile ones?
害があるのも
いるんですか？
They're fine so long as you don't do anything.
（エリアス）
何もしなきゃ
大丈夫だよ
Usually.
おおよそは
おおよそ…
Usually?
（エリアス）
これで３つ目
This is the third one.
Their last request.
最後のお使いさ
Why does the church, um...
エリアスは どうして その…
Why do they ask you to do things?
教会に…
いろいろと言われるんですか？
I made a mistake a while ago.
（エリアス）
昔
やらかしちゃったことがあってね
目を付けられてるんだ
They've had an eye on me ever since.
I don't like dealing with them,
相手するのも面倒だから
so I take care of some of their business
in exchange for their leaving me alone.
あちらのやっかいを
たまに片づけて
見逃してもらってるのさ
Come to think of it, that man
called Elias by a different name.
（チセ）
そういえば
あの男の人がエリアスのことを
違う名前で呼んでたけど
裂き喰らう城(ピルム･ムーリアリス)…
Pilum Murialis.
There's so much I don't know about him.
このヒトのこと
知らないことばかりだ
Right, I forgot.
（エリアス）そうだ 忘れてた
チセ
Chise.
I'd asked Angelica to make this for you.
（エリアス）
アンジェリカに頼んでたものが
出来上がってね
A ring?
指輪？
You know why Sleigh Beggies are short-lived, don't you?
（エリアス）
夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)が
なぜ短命なのか
知っているよね？
We're frail despite our strong ability
to create and soak up magic, right?
魔力を作ったり
吸い取ったりする力が
強い割に
体が
すごくもろいんですよね
Right.
（エリアス）そう
So what you need is a ring to
slow down your production of magic.
そこで必要なのが
魔力の生産を抑える指輪
However, the ring can only do so much.
ただし 指輪にも限度がある
Become excited, and it'll function
more actively, just as your body does.
心が高ぶれば
体と同じように機能も活発になる
So, stay as calm as you can.
だから なるべく冷静でいること
はい
Okay.
It's all right.
（エリアス）大丈夫
As your buyer, I'm responsible for you.
君を買った責任者として
僕も より良い方法を探すから
I'll look for better solutions.
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
The right index finger is the guiding finger.
（アンジェリカ）
“右の人さし指は 導きの指”
P.S. You're not ready for your left ring finger!
“追伸 左の薬指は まだ早い！”
Elias hasn't really said anything
about what happened since then.
（チセ）
あれから
エリアスは あのことには
ほとんど触れないけど…
（エリアス）チセ
Chise.
Coming.
あ… はい
I'd like to assign a familiar to you soon.
（エリアス）
本当は 早く君に 使い魔を
あてがってあげたいんだけど…
A familiar?
（チセ）使い魔？
A creature that consumes its
master's magic, and serves them.
（エリアス）
主人の魔力を食べ
その手足として動くもの
They're useful and loyal,
便利だし 裏切らない
and would make great servants.
いいサーヴァントになるよ
Like the one at Angie-san's place?
（チセ）アンジーさんの所にいた…
They get to be more familiar with their
masters than the masters themselves.
（エリアス）
主人よりも
主人のことに敏感になるから
They'd be perfect for supporting
someone as quiet as you are.
口の重たい君のサポートには
ぴったりなんだよねえ
S-Sorry.
す… すみません
Look, we're here.
（エリアス）ほら 着いたよ
That's the church.
あれが 例の教会だ
Has something happened?
（チセ）何かあったんでしょうか？
Elias?
エリアス？
This could be a bit complicated.
（エリアス）
少し やっかいなことに
なったかもしれないな
急いだほうがいいかもね
We may need to hurry.
I'll go talk to the ones in charge here.
僕は
ここの管理者と話をつけてくる
Go take a look around.
君は先に
少し周囲を見てきてくれ
Let me know if you find anything.
何かあったら 僕に知らせて
Don't put yourself in danger.
むちゃしちゃ ダメだよ
はい
Okay.
All right, get lost.
（警官）ほら 散れ 散れ！
This is awful.
（男性Ａ）こりゃ ひでえな
They're bitten and scratched all over.
（男性Ｂ）
かみ傷と ひっかき傷だらけだぜ
Were there ever any wild dogs around here?
（女性）
この辺に 野犬なんかいたかしら？
Don't look.
（チセ）
見るな 見るな 見るな…
Don't look.
There's something bad growing here.
（チセ）
ここ… 良くないものが湧いてる
Where are you from?
（仮面）
お前は どこから来たんだい？
Where are you from?
Where?
This is one of the bad ones.
（チセ）
これは… ダメなヤツだ
Where are you going?
（仮面）どこへ…
Where?
（チセ）
この手の問いかけに
応えちゃいけない
I can't answer its question.
Where?
Who does the seamless shirt go to?
（仮面）
縫い目のないシャツは 誰に渡す？
Answer even one thing, and it'll take me.
（チセ）
ひと言でも応えたら 連れてかれる
I have to escape.
逃げなきゃ！
I'd let my guard down because
Elias was with me these days.
最近 エリアスが
ずっと そばにいたから油断してた
Where are you going?
（仮面）どこに行くの？
Where to?
どこに？ どこから？
Where from?
どこへ？ どこへ？
Where to?
どこに？ どこから？
Where from?
Where to? Where from?
（ユリシィ）イザベル？
Isabelle.
Where to?!
（仮面）どこへ！
Get lost, scum.
消えろ クズが！
（チセ）
あ… このヒト…
This person... isn't human.
人間(ひと)じゃない
It's not safe here right now
for someone as sensitive as you.
（ユリシィ）
お前みたいに勘のいいヤツは
今 ここは危ない
早く 帰れ
Go home.
U-Uh...
あっ あの ありがとうございま…
Thank you—
What's wrong?!
（チセ）どうしたんですか？
（ユリシィ）ハア… ハア…
These cuts...
（チセ）
この傷って…
Elias.
エリアス…
エリアスを呼ばなきゃ
I need to get Elias.
Or should I treat him with what medicine I have?
（チセ）
それとも
持ってる薬で 手当てだけでも？
You remind me of Isabelle.
（ユリシィ）お前は…
イザベルに似てるな
Yeah.
そうだ… イザベル
Isabelle.
傷が！
Your wounds...
Isabelle...
（ユリシィ）
イザベル… イザベル…
Isabelle...
The black dog...
ブラック･ドッグ…
Isabelle...
（ユリシィ）
イザベル… イザベル…
Isabelle...
血が！
No.
待って！
Wait.
You're way too hurt to move, even for a fairy!
いくら妖精の体でも
それだけ傷が付いてたら
危ないよ！
Bite wounds and shred marks.
（チセ）
かみ傷に 裂かれたみたいな痕
It's a lot like that corpse.
やっぱり さっきの死体と似てる
It wasn't him who did it.
あれは
このヒトがやったんじゃない？
（アリス）おい
You.
Hand over that dog.
その犬 渡せ
You're from before.
あなたは この間の？
I don't have any business with you.
あたしは
てめえを どうこうする気はねえ
さっさと その犬を
渡してくれりゃあ それでいい
Hand over the dog. That's all I ask.
That's not a problem for you, is it?
お前に損はねえだろ？
He helped me.
この子は 私を助けてくれたから
まっとうな理由がなかったら
嫌です
Unless you have a proper reason, I refuse.
Just hand it over!
いいから 渡せ！
そいつを持っていかないと…
I need to take him!
What the hell did you—
てっめえ 何しやが…
（チセ）失敗作だけど
I messed this one up, but it might
actually be useful against humans.
人間相手なら
意外と いい手かも これ
Ulysse.
（イザベル）
ユリシィ…
Ulysse.
ユリシィ！
Come.
おいで
What's the matter, Isabelle? Did they
make fun of you for being a redhead again?
（ユリシィ）
どうした？ イザベル
また 赤毛と そしられたのか
It's such beautiful, sunset-colored hair.
夕暮れ色の きれいな毛なのに
俺は お前の毛が何色だって
愛しているのに
I'd love you no matter what color your hair was.
Isabelle...
イザベル…
Are you up?
（チセ）起きた？
I'm burning fairy repellent.
妖精除(よ)けを焚(た)いてるから
おかしいのは寄らないよ
The weird ones will leave us alone.
Where are we?
（ユリシィ）ここは？
In a forest nearby.
（チセ）近くの林の中だよ
Are your wounds okay?
傷は大丈夫？
I put medicine on them, but...
一応 薬は塗ったけど
You resemble my younger sister.
（ユリシィ）お前は妹に似てる
Your sister?
（チセ）妹？
Isabelle.
（ユリシィ）イザベルだ
She had sunset-colored hair
and eyes like spring seedlings.
夕暮れ色の髪で
春の若い葉に似た目で
She was about your height.
背も お前くらいだった
If you've lost each other,
it's dangerous here, so I'll help find...
（チセ）
もし はぐれたりしてるなら
ここは危ないみたいだし 捜しに…
（ユリシィ）必要ない
There's no need.
あいつは土の下で寝てる
She's sleeping under the dirt.
So she's dead?
（チセ）
死んだってことかな…
You're quite a strange dog.
何だか 変わった犬だね
Dog?
（ユリシィ）犬？
Isabelle and I are both human.
イザベルも俺も 人間だ
I'd watched over her ever since she was little.
（ユリシィ）
あいつが生まれたときから
ずっと見てきたんだ
Ulysse.
ユリシィ
Always.
ずっと ずっと…
I always thought she would call me with that voice.
あの声で呼んでもらえると
思ってたんだ
I've met someone like you before.
前に あなたに似た人と
会ったことがあるよ
Were they able to be with the one they love?
そいつは 好きなもののそばに
いられたのか？
そうといえば そうだし
You could say so.
違うといえば 違うかな
But you could say otherwise, too.
Say what?
（ユリシィ）なんだ それ
Where did you get those wounds?
（チセ）その傷 どうしたの？
（ユリシィ）分からない
I don't know.
Are you all right?
（チセ）大丈夫ですか？
I'm glad the medicine doesn't last very long.
薬の効き目が短くて よかった
What the hell do you think—
てめえ！ どういうつもり…
Alice-san, was it?
（チセ）
アリスさん… でしたっけ？
You scared me a bit, so I took
the liberty of tying your wrists.
ちょっと怖かったんで
縛らせてもらいました
Damn.
You aren't going to do anything?
（アリス）何も… しねえのか？
I have no reason to do anything to you.
（チセ）
私は あなたに
何かする理由はないので
Um...
ええと… じゃあ 質問で
Can I ask you a question, then?
Why do you want him?
なんで この子が欲しいんですか？
Depending on your reason, I may be able to let you go.
理由次第なら あなたを
自由にできるかもしれませんよ
I need him as raw material to make a chimera.
キメラの素材にするためだ
素材？
Material?
キメラって知ってるか？
Do you know what a chimera is?
They're creatures made by
combining two creatures using magic.
魔術で
動物と動物を掛け合わせて造った
別の生き物だ
Some weird brat came to us
asking to help find the materials for it.
それの素材集めを
手伝えとか言って
妙なガキが来やがったんだ
Master refused.
師匠(せんせい)は断った
But there was nothing he could do.
でも どうにもできなくて…
あたしは どうなってもいいけど…
I don't care what happens to me.
You love him, huh?
（チセ）
あの人のことが好きなんだね
おうよ！
Absolutely!
Nothing good's ever happened to me since I was born.
生まれてから
何にもいいことなんか
なかったけどよ
But I had a bit of talent, so Master took me in.
ちっとは才能ってもんが
あったおかげで
あたしは師匠に拾われた
You're the same way, aren't you?
（アリス）てめえも そうだろ？
（チセ）え？
（アリス）あたしは頭は悪いけど
I'm not very smart, but I would do anything for Master.
師匠のためだったら
何でもやろうって思える
I wonder what I think of him.
（チセ）
私は… あのヒトのこと
どう思ってるんだろう
He has ulterior motives, but he's kind.
裏があるとはいえ 優しいし
He's important to me.
大事な人ではあるよね
何て言ったって 放り出されたら
生きていけないし…
And ultimately, I couldn't go on if he kicked me out.
（アリス）
で！ んなこた どうでもいいんだよ
Never mind that.
これが理由だ
I gave you my reason.
Now let me go, already!
さっさと これ 解きやがれ！
（エリアス）ふ〜ん
I see what's going on now.
事情は 大体 分かった
You were hiding him from me!
てめえ 黙ってやがったな！
（チセ）ごめん
Sorry.
（エリアス）
レンフレッドは近くにいるのか？
Is Renfred nearby?
（アリス）
あたしが１人で出てきただけだ
I came out here by myself!
師匠は…
Master is...
Yo, mage.
おい 魔法使い
Why are you guys here?
（アリス）
あんたたち なんで ここにいる？
To inspect that there.
（エリアス）
そこにいる それの検分だよ
A mage? Inspect me?
魔法使いが俺を？ なぜ？
Why?
It's only recently that he awoke as a black dog.
（エリアス）
ブラック･ドッグとして
目覚めたのは 最近か
That thing won't be a problem.
（エリアス）
まあ それは大丈夫だろう
“それ”？
That thing?
ごめん…
Sorry.
（エリアス）それで？
Well?
Like I said, there's some creepy kid threatening us.
（アリス）さっきも言ったとおり
あたしたちは
おかしいガキに脅されている
He took Master's arm as well.
師匠の腕も そいつに取られた
No wonder.
（エリアス）
どうりで
Please.
頼む
Do something about him.
あいつを どうにかしてほしいんだ
How does that benefit us?
（エリアス）僕らに メリットは？
He's already got chimeras wandering around.
（アリス）
あいつは てめえでも
キメラを うろつかせていやがる
The corpse up front and the dog's
wounds are both his chimera's doing.
あの表の死体も
その犬をやったのも
あいつのキメラだ
Concern yourself with the dog,
and your kitten will be in danger, too.
犬に関わるんなら
てめえの子猫も危ねえぞ？
Was that not a good enough reason?
（アリス）
理由が弱いか？
Sure, I don't mind.
（エリアス）まあ かまわないけど
Why the flimsy voice?
（エリアス）
なんだよ その間の抜けた声は
（アリス）いや…
No, I didn't think you'd be so quick to agree.
そんな簡単に
ＯＫ出されるとは思ってなくてよ
If he's left running around, the church
will come complaining to me later, anyway.
（エリアス）放っておいて
教会あたりに がなられるのも
好きではないから
So what does this "kid" look like?
それで あいつっていうのは
どんなヤツなんだ？
I don't really know.
（アリス）よく分からねえんだ
He looks like a kid, but I see
all kinds of things overlapping.
外見はガキなんだけどよ
いろいろなもんが重なって見える
He's, like, blurry.
ブレるっていうか…
He has this...
どうしたの？
What's wrong?
ニタニタ笑う…
...creepy grin.
What are you—
なんだよ てめ…
Renfred's puppy is so poorly trained.
（カルタフィルス）
レンフレッドの子犬は
しつけがなってないなあ
She spilled everything.
み〜んな しゃべっちゃうなんて
くっ… てめえ！
You!
Huh?
（カルタフィルス）あれ？
Did I get the wrong one?
間違えちゃったか…
Oh well, what does it matter?
でも 別にいいよね
That girl's just a guinea pig, isn't she?
どうせ
ただのモルモットなんでしょ？
その子
There's no way you'd become attached to a human.
だって
お前が人間に執着するわけないもの
Right, Pilum Murialis?
そうでしょ？
ピルム･ムーリアリス
Master said he's a mage from a fantasy story.
（アリス）
“おとぎ話の魔法使いだ”と
師匠は言った
At times, he lends a hand,
and at times, he shows his fangs.
ときに 手を差し伸べ
ときに 牙をむく
Something incomplete that tries
to pretend to be human, he said.
人間のふりをしたがる
なり損ないだと
No.
違う
He's not that half-assed.
こいつは
そんな半端なものじゃない
これは…
This thing could never become human.
人間には なれないモノだ
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
The mage becomes a monster.
（チセ）
異形と化した魔法使い
Having lost himself to rage,
he shows his beastly instincts.
怒りに我を忘れ
隠されていた獣の本性が牙をむく
The wounded girl comes to a decision.
そのとき
傷ついた少女が出した答えとは
Elias!
（チセ）エリアス！